insttranslate.com 2017-10-03

# Instant Translate - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Last Updated: Aug 01, 2017

Thank you for using Instant Translate. This Privacy Policy explains our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information that we receive when you use Instant Translate. This Privacy Policy applies to all available Instant Translate Services and Apps (“Instant Translate”) operated by Twopeople Software e.U., a sole-proprietor firm based in Austria. However, they don't apply to anyone else’s websites, services, or applications, even if you can access those through Instant Translate. This Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service (the “Terms”) govern your use of all available Instant Translate Services and Apps (“Instant Translate”), so please read them carefully before using Instant Translate. 

### Information We Collect and How We Use It

 **Information collected using cookies**

If you use our browser apps (for Chrome, Firefox or Opera), we collect certain information through the use of “cookies”, which are small text files that are saved when you access Instant Translate. We may also use cookies to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing and to customize and improve Instant Translate. You can change your browser options to stop automatically accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting cookies. Please note, however, that if you don’t accept cookies, you may not be able to access all portions or features of Instant Translate. Some third-party services providers that we use may also place their own cookies on your browser. Note that this Privacy Policy covers only our use of cookies and does not include use of cookies by such third parties.   
In case you use iOS, Android or Mac versions of Instant Translate, we collect certain information to monitor aggregate usage, whereas no cookies are used.

 **Information related to use of Instant Translate**  
We automatically record information about how a person uses Instant Translate using Google Analytics, including IP addresses, browser types, operating systems, pages or features of Instant Translate that were used and time spent on them, search terms and other statistics. We use and analyze (and may engage third parties to analyze) this information to customize and improve Instant Translate. We also use IP addresses to generate aggregate, non- identifying information about how Instant Translate is used.

 **Location information**

In some cases we collect and store information about where you are located, such as by converting your IP address into a rough geolocation. We may use location information to improve and personalize Instant Translate.

 **Information We Share With Third Parties**

We’ll only share your PII (personally identifiable information) if we use a third-party service provider that requires it, such as for payment processing. If you use browser apps we will collect your non-PII (non-personally identifiable information) such as URLs of visited websites and the time when it occurred (browsing data). Data is collected on anonymous basis and does not contain any sensitive user information such as passwords, bank details, names etc. Collected data is used exceptionally in marketing purposes, but we leave us right so sell the data to third-parties.  
For users from Russia, Ukraine, Belarus and Kazakhstan, in addition to the anonymous browsing data collection, Instant Translate shows a promotional banner from Yandex.Sovetnik (https://sovetnik.yandex.ru/) on online store pages to offer a better price for a specific product, whereas any personal information is collected.  
Please note that both data collection and Yandex.Sovetnik can be disabled in application settings to stop accordingly collecting anonymous browsing data or showing a promotional banner. Thus, no data will be collected or transmitted to our servers.  
If you use our apps for iOS, Android or Mac, any of your data is collected or transmitted to our servers in any case.  
In all applications, all the settings and history of translations are stored exceptionally on your device and are not transmitted to any third parties or our servers. 

### Changes to Privacy Policy

Any information that we collect is subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time such information is collected. We may, however, revise the Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes may be posted to our website or within our Apps, so please check that regularly. The most current version will always be posted on our Privacy Policy page.

### Contact Information

If you have any specific questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Twopeople Software e.U.  
Novaragasse 36A  
1020 Vienna, Austria  

* * *
